Guide to the Ralph Wright Curtis papers, [ca.1872-1967]
Curtis, Ralph Wright papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ralph Wright Curtis papers, [ca.1872-1967]
21-25-1406
Ralph Wright Curtis, 1878-1968.
3.5 cubic feet
Correspondence, articles, genealogical material, photographs, slides, maps, plaque, medal, news clippings, notebooks, books, and periodicals.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence; articles; genealogical material; photographs; slides; postcards; Christmas cards; letters from students and friends on his retirement from Cornell; material on the funeral of Harriet Curtis; plaque from the Garden Club of Ithaca; medal from the Federated Garden Clubs of New York State; articles on Cornell; maps and informational publications regarding New York State parks; news clippings and other printed matter; notebooks; and periodicals related to horticulture and gardens.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Ralph W. Curtis was a Professor of Ornamental Horticulture at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence; articles; genealogical material; photographs; slides; postcards; Christmas cards; letters from students and friends on his retirement from Cornell; material on the funeral of Harriet Curtis; plaque from the Garden Club of Ithaca; medal from the Federated Garden Clubs of New York State; articles on Cornell; maps and informational publications regarding New York State parks; news clippings and other printed matter; notebooks; and periodicals related to horticulture and gardens.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Curtis, Ralph W., (Ralph Wright), 1878-1968.; Curtis, Harriet.
Titles:
Cornell plantations.
Subjects:
Horticulture.; Horticulturists.; College teachers.
Places:
Chicago (Ill.)--Parks.
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.; Maps.; Photographs.; Postcards.; Slides (photographs).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Genealogical, Biographical & Personal Material
Boxes: 1
Series II. Correspondence
Boxes: 1 & 4
Series III. Cornell University
Boxes: 2
Series IV. Community & Professional Activity
Boxes: 1
Series V. Photographs
Boxes: 3 & 5
Series VI. Miscellany
Boxes: 1, 2, & 3
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Genealogical, Biographical & Personal Material
    - Chronicles of the O.F. Curtis Family, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Otis Freeman Curtis: His Story and Ours, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Curtis and Olds Family Genealogy, 1962, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Curtis, Olds, and Cheney Round Robin, June 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Family of Baldwin & Diantha Olds by C. Burnell Olds, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - LOVE: The Issue by Charles Burnell Olds, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Genealogical and Biographical Notices of the Descendants of Sir John Wright of Essex, Eng. In England and America by Curtis Wright (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - re: Rev. Charles B. Curtis, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - re: Harriet Peasley Curtis' Death, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Charles B. & Harriet Curtis' Certificates as Members of the Industrial Missionary Association of Alabama, 1903-1920 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ralph W. Curtis: Personal and Biographical (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - [Ralph W. Curtis]: Notebooks (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - [Ralph W. Curtis]: Notebooks (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ralph W. Curtis: Retirement, June 20, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Ralph W. Curtis: Achievements Made Since Retirement, April 1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - [Curtis Family Member]: Journal, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series II. Correspondence
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, August 18, 1907-1943 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1944-October 1945 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, November 1945-December 1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1954 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence re: Aphids on Viburnum Opulus, 1952, 1953, & 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: Arnold Arboretum, 1903-1904, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence: Edith Beasley, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: Grace Blanche, 1946 & 1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: Herbert M. Blanche, 1945, 1954, & 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: C.D. Bostwick re: H.B. MacNamee, March 7, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Donald J. Bushey, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Jack Caddick, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: Margaret Clausen re: Harriet Curtis' Death & Funeral, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence: Margaret Clausen, 1945-1952 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence: Cornell Alumni News, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: Charles B. Curtis, 1907 & 1941 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: [Harriett] Curtis, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence: Ralph W. Curtis - Curtis Budget Letter, April 10, 1935-February 24, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence re: Flouridation, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence re: Ginko Biloba, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence: Bernard Harkness, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence re: Herbarium - Florida Trip, 1938-1945 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: Hick's Family, 1948 & n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence: Ralph S. Jackson re: Perm-a-nest, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence: Frederick Jeffers, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence: Letchworth Park Forest & Arboretum, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence: Vaughan MacCaughey, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence: Albert Russell Mann, 1907, 1922, 1927 & 1929 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence: Arthur L. Munson, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence: Burnell Olds, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence: Dr. A.M.S. Pridham re: Community Planting in Ithaca, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence: Robert Reich, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence: Eloise [Sisson], 1945 & 1958 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence: William A. Strong, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence: Jack [Taylor], 1945 & n.d. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence: Rebecca [Thatcher], 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence: Robert H. Treman, 1926 & n.d. (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence: Paul Yashin, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence: Scrapbook of Letters re: Ralph W. Curtis' Retirement (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Scrapbooks of Letters re: Ralph W. Curtis' Retirement (Box 4)
- Series III. Cornell University
    - re: Agriculture Products and Recommendations (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Alpha Zeta (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Addresses for the Bailey Hortorium (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Association of Class Secretaries: Meeting, June 13, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Campus Tree Committee, May 25, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Class of 1901 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Department of Agricultural Engineering: Telephone Directory, September 1961 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Department of Entomology: Dust, Spray and Gas Masks, January 7, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Landscape Art: Planting List, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Cornell Arboretum (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cornell Arboretum: Correspondence & Reports (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cornell Arboretum: Letters of Support (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Cornell Fund (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Cornell Plantations (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Cornell Shrub Garden - Caldwell Hall (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Gamma Alpha (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Laboratory of Ornithology (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Pi Alpha Xi (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Topiary Club Talk, March 10, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - University Faculty: Correspondence, Meeting Minutes & Committees (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Paul Yashin (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Floriculture & Ornamental Horticulture Program & Class Material
    - Department of Floriculture & Ornamental Horticulture: Course Material, November 1929-December 1935 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Department of Floriculture & Ornamental Horticulture: Course Material, February 1936-September 1937 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Department of Floriculture & Ornamental Horticulture: Course Material, February 1938-October 1940 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Department of Floriculture & Ornamental Horticulture: Course Material, January-February 1941 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Department of Floriculture & Ornamental Horticulture: Course Material, March 1941-December 1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Department of Floriculture & Ornamental Horticulture: Course Material, January 1943-May 1947 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Department of Floriculture & Ornamental Horticulture: Course Material, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Key to Woody Ornamentals with Notes on Landscape Values and Cultural Requirments I. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Key to Woody Ornamentals with Notes on Landscape Values and Cultural Requirments II. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Notes on Woody Plant Materials for Landscape Planting, by R.W. Curtis & J.F. Cornman, July 1, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Notes on Woody Plant Materials for Landscape Planting, by Ralph W. Curtis, John F. Cornman & Robert G. Mower (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Course Material & Papers: Drafts, May 1932-January 1948 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Course Material & Papers: Drafts, 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Course Material & Papers: Drafts, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Visit to Rochester Parks - Lilacs, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Laboratory and Field Work in Nature Study: Course Purpose and Description (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Publications
    - The Baileyman, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - re: Liberty Hyde Bailey (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Agriculture Experiment Station Bulletins (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - The Cornell Countryman, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - New York State College of Agriculture Cornell Extension Bulletin (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Extension Service News by the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell University (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Current Episodes by the New York State Extension Service, June 1956 & April 1959 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Foto Facts, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Newsclippings re: Cornell University (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Cornell Recommendations for Commercial Floriculture Crops (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - 1957 Recommendations for Trees, Shrubs, and Turf & Revised 1962 edition (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous Publications re: Agriculture (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - College of Agriculture: A University Education in Agricultural Science (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Series IV. Community & Professional Activity
    - American Horticultural Council: Citation of Merit, October-November 1953 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Arnold Arboretum, 1943, 1945-1946, & n.d. (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Massachusettes Horticultural Society, 1917, 1955, & n.d. (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - New York State Flower Grower's, Inc.: Report on Soils Laboratory, Cornell University, January 4, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - First Congregational Church, Ithaca, N.Y., 1945-1952 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Garden Club of Ithaca: Clippings re: Wall Plaque, March 1954 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Pleasant Grove Cemetary Association, Inc., 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Union Free School District, Cayuga Heights, Ithaca, N.Y. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Ithaca Journal
    - Forsythia Drive: Letter to the Editor, March 1953 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Ithaca Trees and Shrubs Series: Drafts, April-September 1953 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Ithaca Trees and Shrubs Series: Drafts, September-October 1953 & n.d. (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Ithaca Trees and Shrubs Series: Drafts (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Ithaca Trees and Shrubs Series: Drafts (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Ithaca Trees and Shrubs Series: Correspondence & Documents, November 1953 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Series V. Photographs, Negatives & Slides
  - Miscellaneous Olds, Curtis, and Cheney Family Photographs (Box 3 & 5)
  - Miscellaneous Cornell University: Faculty, Students, & Campus (Box 3 & 5)
  - Miscellaneous Floriculture & Horticulture (Box 3 & 5)
- Series VI. Miscellany
  - Horticulture Information
    - Miscellaneous Plant Information (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Diseases & Pests (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Dutch Elm Disease (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Hardiness Zones of the United States and Canada by Donald Wyman (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Reference List of Perennials (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Turfgrass (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Weeds (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Publications re: Horticulture and Gardens
    - American Association of Nurserymen: Report of the Committee on Botanical Gardens and Arboretums, July 1931 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Co-Op Bulletin Ithaca, N.Y., August & December 1958 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Farm Research, October 1955 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Journal of the New England Botanical Club re: Rhodora (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous Agriculture & Horticulture Publications (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - New York State Flower Grower's Incorporated Bulletin (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - New York State Nurserymen's Association: New York Nursery Notes (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - New York State Turf Association Bulletin (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Ornamentals Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Shade Tree Digest (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - The Garden vol. II. (Box 4)
    - The Garden vol. III. (Box 4)
    - Garden and Forest vol. I., 1888 (Box 4)
    - Garden and Forest vol. II., 1889 (Box 4)
  - Other Publications
    - Dodge News Magazine, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Grace Before Meals, by William L. Curtis, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - re: New York State Parks (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Verses, by Minnie Curtis Waite, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Miscellaneous Newsclippings & Advertisements (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Other Miscellany
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Miscellaneous Financial Records (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Miscellaneous Papers & Reports (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Plaque from the Garden Club of Ithaca, 1954 (Box 3)
    - Medal from the Federated Garden Clubs of New York State (Box 3)